Rajul Dixit Frontend Developer

- +44 07442630605
- Flat 9 6 Stoddart way, Edinburgh, Scotland, United Kingdom, EH7 4FD
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajul-dixit-5522b310b/
- https://github.com/rajuldixit

Profile

Front-End Developer with 6+ years of relevant experience building banking projects and apps in fast paced, collaborative environments. Highly skilled in HTML/CSS, JavaScript/Angular/React, Node JS, Express JS. My role is to write and style the front-end components that meet the requirements of our mocks and fulfill our user stories, I also monitor and process pull requests for production deployments. Well-versed in Scrum and Agile.

Professional Experience

UI Developer, Purview Services

July 2022 – present

Edinburgh, Scotland

Software Consultant, Nu10

December 2021 - June 2022

Remote, India

Frontend Developer, Capita

February 2021 - February 2022

Pune, India

Software Development Engineer,

Hyperstate Technology

February 2019 - February 2021

Pune, India

Associate Frontend Developer, Capco

August 2017 – February 2019

Pune, India

Projects

Shared Business Profile,

July 2022 - September 2023

React js, Redux, Redux-thunk, Express js, Ramda

SBP has two flows, one is for customer support and other one is for

maintaining/reviewing customer query process. here customers can make an enquiry through telephone or email, and based on the given details we can resolve/decline/cancel

Solar Panels, SunContract, React is,

April 2022 - June 2022

Redux-toolkit, Redux-thunk, HTML5, SCSS, Express

Js, Node Js

This is a dashboard for people to buy/sell Solar panels, where they can view analytics about the solar history.

They can make an offer to any solar panel they are interested in, also the project has notifications, activities and profile of the user

CryptoBunny, React js, Redux-thunk, HTML5, CSS3

December 2021 – March 2022

CryptoBunny is basically a cryptocurrency app, where user can come either via some other platform to pay the bill using cryptocurrency or

they can create their profile and use for personal usage. Their user can deposit, transfer the crypto.

Pay360 Evolve, React js, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

February 2021 - February 2022

This product is related to payment handling, where various merchants can enroll themselves to our system, where they can accept or make payments. We have integrated few payment methods like Paypal, Apple Pay, Credit card, Debit card

Console Dashboard, Angular 6, HTML5, CSS3

February 2019 - February 2021

Console Dashboard is divided into 3 sections, 1. Content Management, 2. Project Management, Analytics. For Content Management, This is the

place where we can upload assets (images, videos, text files, pdfs) to create Campaign. For Project Management, Project manager can create

project and sectionized it, and assign respective team members to work on their specific tasks. For Analytics, we have D3.js and apex charts, where we can view the report in graphical manner.

SCB Abacus

August 2017 – February 2019

Siam Commercial Bank (SCB) project Abacus is business loan application, where banking customers can apply for loan to start the small

scale to large scale business, this project involves level of authentication and verification before load approval.

Education

Master of Computer Application(MCA),

June 2013 - June 2016 | Pune, India

Pune University

Bachelors of Computer Application (BCA),,

June 2010 – May 2013 | Agra, India

Agra University

Skills

Redux, Redux-toolkit, Redux-thunk SCSS

Express Js • • • • • Angular • • • • •

Node Js